boomkat.com 2018-10-23

# Boomkat

### CONTENTS OF THIS NOTICE

  1. Introduction
  2. What is Boomkat?
  3. Explaining the legal bases we rely on
  4. When do we collect your personal data?
  5. What sort of personal data do we collect?
  6. How and why do we use your personal data?
  7. Combining your data for personalised direct marketing
  8. How we protect your personal data
  9. How long will we keep your personal data?
  10. Who do we share your personal data with?
  11. Where your personal data may be processed
  12. What are your rights over your personal data?
  13. How can you stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing?
  14. Contacting the Regulator
  15. If you live outside the UK
  16. Any questions?
  17. Cookie Notice

### 1\. INTRODUCTION

This Privacy Notice explains in detail the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us. It also explains how we store and handle that data, and keep it safe. Boomkat is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

We appreciate that this Notice contains a lot of information but we want you to be fully informed about your rights, and how Boomkat uses your data.

We hope the following sections will answer any questions you have but, if not, please do get in touch with us. It’s likely that we’ll need to update this Privacy Notice from time to time. We’ll notify you of any significant changes, but you’re welcome to come back and check it whenever you wish.

### 2\. WHAT IS BOOMKAT?

Boomkat (which we’ll refer to as ‘the Group’ in this document) is a specialist online record store based in Manchester, UK, made up of of the following related businesses:

  * Boomkat Limited
  * Boomkat Digital Limited

For simplicity throughout this notice, ‘we’ and ‘us’ means the Group and its brands.

### 3\. EXPLAINING THE LEGAL BASES WE RELY ON

The law on data protection sets out a number of different reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data, including:

**Consent**

In specific situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent.

For example, when you tick a box to receive email newsletters.

When collecting your personal data, we’ll always make clear to you which data is necessary in connection with a particular service.

**Contractual obligations**

In certain circumstances, we need your personal data to comply with our contractual obligations.

For example, if you order an item from us for home delivery, we’ll collect your address details to deliver your purchase, and pass them to our courier. 

**Legal compliance**

If the law requires us to, we may need to collect and process your data.  

For example, we can pass on details of people involved in fraud or other criminal activity affecting the Group to law enforcement.

**Legitimate interest**

In specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests. For example, we might combine the anonymised shopping history of customers to identify trends and ensure we can keep up with demand, or develop new products/services.

### 4\. WHEN DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

  * When you visit our website, and use your account to buy products and services, or redeem vouchers from the Group online.
  * When you make an online purchase and check out as a guest (in which case we just collect transaction-based data).
  * When you create an account with us.
  * When you make enquiries via social media.
  * When you contact us by any other means with queries, complaints etc

### 5\. WHAT SORT OF PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT?

  * If you have a web account with us: your name, billing/delivery address, orders and receipts, email and telephone number. For your security, we’ll also keep an encrypted record of your login password.
  * Details of your interactions with us online.
  * For example, we collect details of purchases you made, items viewed or added to your basket, wish list choices, voucher redemptions
  * Details of your shopping preferences (for example what products you redeem gifts vouchers against).
  * Information gathered by the use of cookies in your web browser. Learn more about how we use cookies by reading our Cookies Notice.
  * Tokenised payment card information. Encrypted payment details are sent to and managed securely by our payment service provider. We do not keep a record of your credit card, apart from the card type and last four digits.
  * To deliver the best possible web experience, we collect technical information about your internet connection and browser as well as the country where your computer is located, the web pages viewed during your visit and any search terms you entered.
  * Your social media username, if you interact with us through those channels, to help us respond to your comments, questions or feedback.

### 6\. HOW AND WHY DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We want to give you the best possible customer experience. We use your personal data in order to fulfil your orders, deal with your queries and for marketing new products.

The data privacy law allows this as part of our legitimate interest in understanding our customers and providing the highest levels of service.

Of course, if you wish to change how we use your data, you’ll find details in the ‘What are my rights?’ section below. Remember, if you choose not to share your personal data with us, or refuse certain contact permissions, we might not be able to provide some services you’ve asked for. For example, if you’ve asked us to let you know when an item comes back into stock, we can’t do that if you’ve withdrawn your general consent to hear from us.

Here’s how we’ll use your personal data and why:

  * To process any orders that you make through our website. If we don’t collect your personal data during checkout, we won’t be able to process your order and comply with our legal obligations.
  * For example, your details may need to be passed to a third party to supply or deliver the product or service that you ordered, and we may keep your details for a reasonable period afterwards in order to fulfil any contractual obligations such as refunds, guarantees and so on.
  * To respond to your queries, refund requests and complaints. Handling the information you sent enables us to respond. We may also keep a record of these for the purpose of any future communication with us and to demonstrate how we communicated with you throughout. We do this on the basis of our contractual obligations to you, our legal obligations and our legitimate interests in providing you with the best service and understanding how we can improve our service based on your experience.
  * To protect our business and your account from fraud and other illegal activities. This includes using your personal data to maintain, update and safeguard your account. We’ll also monitor your browsing activity with us to quickly identify and resolve any problems and protect the integrity of our websites. We’ll do all of this as part of our legitimate interest.
  * For example, by our system checking your encrypted password when you login and using automated monitoring of IP addresses to identify possible fraudulent log-ins from unexpected locations.
  * To process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests. This also helps to protect our customers from fraud.
  * If we discover any criminal activity or alleged criminal activity through our use of fraud monitoring and suspicious transaction monitoring, we will process this data for the purposes of preventing or detecting unlawful acts. We aim to protect the individuals we interact with from criminal activities.
  * With your consent, we will keep you informed by email about new products and services including special offers, discounts, promotions, events, competitions and so on.
  * Of course, you are free to opt out of hearing from us by any of these channels at any time.
  * To send you communications required by law or which are necessary to inform you about our changes to the services we provide you. For example, updates to this Privacy Notice, product recall notices, and legally required information relating to your orders. These service messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email. If we do not use your personal data for these purposes, we would be unable to comply with our legal obligations.
  * To develop, test and improve the systems, services and products we provide to you. We’ll do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.
  * For example, we’ll record your browser’s Session ID to help us understand more when you leave us feedback about any problems you’re having
  * To comply with our contractual or legal obligations to share data with law enforcement (for example, when a court order is submitted to share data with law enforcement agencies or a court of law).
  * To build a picture of who you are and what you like, and to inform our business decisions, we’ll combine data captured from across the Group as we have described in the section 'What Sort of Personal Data do we collect?' We’ll do this on the basis of our legitimate business interest.
  * Sometimes, we’ll need to share your details with a third party who is providing a service (such as delivery couriers). Without sharing your personal data, we’d be unable to fulfil your request.

### 7\. MARKETING

If you choose to subscribe to our newsletters we will send you marketing updates about new products. You can unsubscribe from our newsletters at any time by clicking on the links at the bottom of each one.

### 8\. HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We know how much data security matters to all our customers. With this in mind we will treat your data with the utmost care and take all appropriate steps to protect it. 

We secure access to all transactional areas of our websites and apps using ‘https’ technology.

Access to your personal data is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as payment card information) is secured by SSL encryption.

We regularly monitor our system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and we carry out penetration testing to identify ways to further strengthen security.

### 9\. HOW LONG WILL WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

Whenever we collect or process your personal data, we’ll only keep it for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. 

At the end of that retention period, your data will either be deleted completely or anonymised, for example by aggregation with other data so that it can be used in a non-identifiable way for statistical analysis and business planning.

### 10\. WHO DO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH?

We sometimes share your personal data with trusted third parties. 

For example, delivery couriers, for fraud management, to handle complaints, to help us personalise our recommendations to you and so on. 

Here’s the policy we apply to those organisations to keep your data safe and protect your privacy:

  * We provide only the information they need to perform their specific services.
  * They may only use your data for the exact purposes we specify in our contract with them.
  * We work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected at all times.
  * If we stop using their services, any of your data held by them will either be deleted or rendered anonymous.
  * Examples of the kind of third parties we work with are:
  * IT companies who support our website and other business systems.
  * Operational companies such as delivery couriers.
  * Direct marketing companies who help us manage our electronic communications with you.

Sharing your data with third parties for their own purposes:

We will only do this in very specific circumstances, for example:

  * For fraud management, we may share information about fraudulent or potentially fraudulent activity in our premises or systems. This may include sharing data about individuals with law enforcement bodies.
  * We may also be required to disclose your personal data to the police or other enforcement, regulatory or Government body, in your country of origin or elsewhere, upon a valid request to do so. These requests are assessed on a case-by-case basis and take the privacy of our customers into consideration.
  * We may, from time to time, expand, reduce or sell the Group and this may involve the transfer of divisions or the whole business to new owners. If this happens, your personal data will, where relevant, be transferred to the new owner or controlling party, under the terms of this Privacy Notice.

For further information please contact our Data Manager.

### 11\. WHERE YOUR PERSONAL DATA MAY BE PROCESSED

Sometimes we will need to share your personal data with third parties and suppliers outside the European Economic Area (EEA), such as Australia or the USA.

**International orders**

If you are based outside the UK and place an order with us, we will transfer the personal data that we collect from you to the Group in the UK.

**Protecting your data outside the EEA**

The EEA includes all EU Member countries as well as Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway. We may transfer personal data that we collect from you to third-party data processors in countries that are outside the EEA.

For example, this might be required in order to fulfil your order, process your payment details or provide support services.

If we do this, we have procedures in place to ensure your data receives the same protection as if it were being processed inside the EEA. For example, our contracts with third parties stipulate the standards they must follow at all times. If you wish for more information about these contracts please contact our Data Manager.

Any transfer of your personal data will follow applicable laws and we will treat the information under the guiding principles of this Privacy Notice. 

### 12\. WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS OVER YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

**An overview of your different rights**

You have the right to request:

  * Access to the personal data we hold about you, free of charge in most cases.
  * The correction of your personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete.
  * For example, when you withdraw consent, or object and we have no legitimate overriding interest, or once the purpose for which we hold the data has come to an end (such as the end of a warranty).
  * That we stop using your personal data for direct marketing (either through specific channels, or all channels).
  * That we stop any consent-based processing of your personal data after you withdraw that consent.
  * Review by a Partner of any decision made based solely on automatic processing of your data (i.e. where no human has yet reviewed the outcome and criteria for the decision).

You have the right to request a copy of any information about you that the Group holds at any time, and also to have that information corrected if it is inaccurate. To ask for your information, please contact Data Manager, Boomkat, Second Floor, Swan Building, 20 Swan Street, Manchester, M4 5JW, or email [data@boomkat.com](mailto:data@boomkat.com). To ask for your information to be amended, please update your online account, or contact our Customer Services team.

If we choose not to action your request we will explain to you the reasons for our refusal.

**Your right to withdraw consent**

Whenever you have given us your consent to use your personal data, you have the right to change your mind at any time and withdraw that consent.

**Where we rely on our legitimate interest**

In cases where we are processing your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest, you can ask us to stop for reasons connected to your individual situation. We must then do so unless we believe we have a legitimate overriding reason to continue processing your personal data.

**Checking your identity**

To protect the confidentiality of your information, we will ask you to verify your identity before proceeding with any request you make under this Privacy Notice. If you have authorised a third party to submit a request on your behalf, we will ask them to prove they have your permission to act.

### 13\. HOW CAN YOU STOP THE USE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR DIRECT MARKETING?

There are several ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us:

  * Click the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any newsletter that we send you. We will then stop any further emails from that particular division.
  * Email us at [data@boomkat.com](mailto:data@boomkat.com)
  * Write to us at Data Manager, Boomkat, Second Floor, Swan Building, 20 Swan Street, Manchester, M4 5JW

Please note that you may continue to receive communications for a short period after changing your preferences while our systems are fully updated.

### 14\. CONTACTING THE REGULATOR

If you feel that your data has not been handled correctly, or you are unhappy with our response to any requests you have made to us regarding the use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

You can contact them by calling 0303 1231113 or go online to [www.ico.org.uk/concerns](https://www.ico.org.uk/concerns).

If you are based outside the UK, you have the right to lodge your complaint with the relevant data protection regulator in your country of residence. Details can be found in Section 16.

### 15\. IF YOU LIVE OUTSIDE THE UK

**For all non-UK customers**

By using our services or providing your personal data to us, you expressly consent to the processing of your personal data by us or on our behalf. Of course, you still have the right to ask us not to process your data in certain ways, and if you do so, we will respect your wishes.

Sometimes we’ll need to transfer your personal data between countries to enable us to supply the goods or services you’ve requested. In the ordinary course of business, we may transfer your personal data from your country of residence to ourselves and to third parties located in the UK.

By dealing with us, you are giving your consent to this overseas use, transfer and disclosure of your personal data outside your country of residence for our ordinary business purposes.

This may occur because our information technology storage facilities and servers are located outside your country of residence, and could include storage of your personal data on servers in the UK.

We’ll ensure that reasonable steps are taken to prevent third parties outside your country of residence using your personal data in any way that’s not set out in this Privacy Notice. We’ll also make sure we adequately protect the confidentiality and privacy of your personal data.

**Australia**

For the purposes of this Privacy Notice, ‘personal data’ means any information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable, whether or not the information or opinion is true, and whether or not the information or opinion is recorded in a material form.

If you are in Australia you may submit any questions, comments or complaints to our UK-based Data Protection Officer who will come back to you within 30 days.

If you are contacting us to complain about an alleged breach of this Privacy Notice or our legal privacy obligations, please provide us with as much detail as possible in relation to your complaint.  

We will take every privacy complaint seriously and assess it with the aim of resolving all issues quickly and efficiently.  We’d be grateful for your cooperation with us during this process by providing us with any relevant information that we made need.

If we have not come back to you within 30 days, or you are not happy with the response that you’ve received, you may submit a complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner. 

We are committed to keeping your personal information secure and will take all reasonable precautions to protect it from loss, misuse or unauthorised access or alteration. However, except to the extent liability cannot be excluded due to the operation of statute, we exclude all liability (including in negligence) for the consequences of any unauthorised access to, disclosure of, misuse of or loss or corruption of your personal information.

Nothing in this Privacy Notice restricts, excludes or modifies or purports to restrict, exclude or modify any statutory consumer rights under any applicable law including the Competition and Consumer Act 2010 (Cth).  

**USA**

To learn more about our cookies and website ‘track’ and ‘do not track’ practices please see our Cookies Notice.

**Canada**

As your data may be transferred to third parties outside Canada, local police or other enforcement, regulatory or Government bodies may have access to that data, with or without our knowledge.

The personal data we process may be accessed by people within the Group, or by our third-party service providers, who require access for the purposes indicated in this Privacy Notice, or as may be permitted or required by applicable law. The personal data we collect is largely held in the UK.  

If you have any questions, please contact our Data Protection Officer.

If you feel that your data has not been handled correctly, or you are unhappy with our response to any requests you have made to us regarding the use of your personal information, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada, or in some Canadian provinces, your local Privacy Commissioner.

**South Korea, Malaysia, Singapore, Qatar**

Terms used in this Privacy Notice shall have the meanings assigned to them by the Personal Data Protection Act 2010 (also known as the PDPA).  

By placing an order with us, opening an account, browsing our website and/or agreeing to receive digital direct marketing communications, you agree that we may process your personal data as described in this Privacy Notice and our Cookies Notice, including for analytics and research into website use.

**Hong Kong**

When you agree to receive direct marketing emails from us, we’ll send you promotions on products we sell.

If you are in Hong Kong you may submit a complaint to our UK-based Data Protection Officer who will come back to you within 30 days. If we have not come back to you or you are not happy with the response that you receive, you may submit a complaint to the Office of the Privacy Commissioner for Personal Data.

### 16\. ANY QUESTIONS?

We hope this Privacy Notice has been helpful in setting out the way we handle your personal data and your rights to control it.

If you have any questions that haven’t been covered, please contact our Data Protection Officer who will be pleased to help you

  * Email us at [data@boomkat.com](mailto:data@boomkat.com)
  * Write to the Data Manager, Boomkat, Second Floor, Swan Building, 20 Swan Street, Manchester, M4 5JW

### 17\. COOKIE NOTICE

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. Boomkat uses cookies to keep track of what you have in your crate, and to remember you when you return to our website.

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website (we can only provide you with certain personalised features of our website by using them) and it also allows us to improve our website. We don't store personally identifiable information such as credit card details in cookies we create.

To make purchases on boomkat.com you need to have cookies enabled via your browser. Most web browsers have cookies enabled, but check the 'Help' menu of your particular browser (or your mobile phone manual) to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Alternatively if you want to restrict, block or delete cookies from our website you can do this using your browser.
